lingo24.com 2018-06-02

# Privacy and terms | Lingo24 UK

### Who are “we”?

When we refer to ‘we’ (or ‘our’ or ‘us’), that means Lingo24 Limited and all its wholly owned subsidiaries.  Our company is registered in Scotland with the registration number is SC222407 and registered office of 18 Torphichen Street, Edinburgh, EH3 8JB, Scotland.

Whilst our headquarters are in the United Kingdom, we operate and have offices all over the world, with the following subsidiary companies:

• Panama – Lingo24 Inc

• Romania – Lingo24 Srl

• Philippines – Lingo24 PH Inc

Address details for all Lingo24 offices are available on our [Contact us](http://www.lingo24.com/contact/) page.

### How do we collect data?

When you visit our websites or use our services, we collect personal data. The ways we collect it can be broadly categorised into the following:

_Information you provide to us directly_ \- when you visit or use some parts of our websites and/or services we might ask you to provide personal data to us. For example, we ask for your contact information when you sign up for our ordering portal, you download marketing material, submit a job application, contact us with questions or request support. If you don’t want to provide us with personal data, you don’t have to, but it might mean you can’t use some parts of our websites or services.  

_Information we collect automatically_ \-  We collect some information about you automatically when you visit our websites or use our services, like your IP address and device type. We also collect information when you navigate through our websites and services, including what pages you looked at and what links you clicked on. This information is useful for us as it helps us get a better understanding of how you’re using our websites and services so that we can continue to provide the best experience possible.  

_Information you generate_ \- When you use our services, our linguists or your in-market reviewers, also generate data, including:

• Translation memory - containing previous translations conducted on your behalf that either a) Lingo24 has performed or b) you provide to use at on-boarding or as part on on-going synchronisation. This also contains metadata on who did what.

• Glossary entries -  containing approved or rejected terms that should or should not be used within your translations.

• Performance metrics - such as the throughput of translation, editing distance of review changes, and time spent on content.

Where we collect personal data, we’ll only process it:

• to perform a contract with you, or

• where we have legitimate interests to process the personal data and they’re not

• overridden by your rights, or

• in accordance with a legal obligation, or

• where we have your consent.

If we don’t collect your personal data, we may be unable to provide you with all our services, and some functions and features on our websites may not be available to you.   

### Cookies and our use of them

Cookies are small files saved to the user's computer's hard drive that track, save and store information about the user's interactions and usage of the website. This allows the website, through its server to provide the users with a tailored experience within this website.

This website uses cookies to better the users experience while visiting the website. Users are advised that if they wish to deny the use and saving of cookies from this website onto their computers hard drive they should take necessary steps within their web browsers security settings to block all cookies from this website and it’s external serving vendors.

The website does not set its own cookies but we do use the following third-party cookies to enable third party features or functionality to be provided on or through our websites and services:  

• Google Analytics (Analytics) - Google Analytics uses cookies to help us analyse how our users use our websites and services. You can find out more about this service and how Google uses your data at [http://www.google.com/analytics](https://www.google.com/analytics/) and [www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/)

• Facebook (Analytics) - we use Facebook as a medium to talk to customers and to measure effectiveness of campaigns

• LinkedIn(Analytics) - we use LinkedIn as a medium to talk to customers and to measure effectiveness of campaigns

• DoubleClick (Analytics) \- we use DoubleClick to help manage our digital marketing activities

• GetResponse (Analytics and Marketing) \- we use GetResponse as a marketing automation platform so we can personalise your experience with us

• Embedly (Analytics and Marketing) \- we use Embedly to support social sharing of content and tracking of engagement.

### What do we use it for?

We use your personal data to operate our websites and provide you with any services you’ve requested, and to manage our relationship with you.  We also use your personal data for other purposes, such as to:

_Communicate with you_ \- including:

• Providing you with information you’ve requested from us like case studies or information we are required to send to you

• Operational communications, like changes to our websites and services, security updates, or assistance with using our websites and services

• Marketing communications (about Lingo24 or another product or service we think you might be interested in) in accordance with your marketing preferences

_Provide support to you_ \- including:

• Assisting with the resolution of technical support issues or other issues relating to the websites or services raised through our Service Desk.

• Providing assistance to queries or concerns raised on our website chat system.

_Enhance and develop our services_ \- including:

• Tracking and monitoring your use of our websites and services so we can understand how you use our services.

• Carrying out analysis of our websites and services so that we can optimise your user experience and provide you with more efficient tools

_Market to you_ \- including:

• Sending you relevant marketing communications

• Display targeted advertising to you online – through our own websites and services or through third party websites and their platforms.

### International Data Transfers

Whilst Lingo24 is based in European Union (EU) and our servers and data is hosted there, Lingo24 is a truly global company.

With our policy of using in-country linguists to support quality of translations and global hubs to support 24x7 delivery, we often perform data transfers outside of the European Economic Area ("EEA") when these teams access our systems hosted in Europe.

We will only conduct these data transfers where the service provision and time-zone of the language your request requires it to processed by a local third-party linguist or Lingo24 subsidiary hub.

Where we transfer personal data outside of the EEA, we ensure the party has taken such measures as are necessary to ensure the transfer is in compliance with relevant Data Protection Legislation.

### Your rights

The personal data we hold on you is your data. This means you have certain rights that you are able to exercise on our processing of it.

For marketing communications, you can ask us not to send you these at any time – just follow the unsubscribe instructions contained in the marketing communication, or raise a Consent Withdrawal Request at http://security.lingo24.com

You also have additional rights including to :

• Know what personal data we hold about you

• Request a copy of your personal data

• Ask us to restrict processing your personal data and/or delete it

You can exercise these rights at any time by raising a request at [http://security.lingo24.com](http://security.lingo24.com/).  We will review and investigate any request you make, and try to get back to you within a reasonable time frame.

This policy is subject to change without prior written notice.

Published 22nd May 2018

###
